## **DEJA SCOTT**

#### **Contact Me**

Phone (123)-456-7890

Email ds17@email.sc.edu

GitHub https://github.com/DS-77

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/deja-s

#### **About Me**

Motivated Computer Science graduate pursuing a Master's and PhD with a concentration in computer vision. With over six years of experience in web application development and five years in research, I am dedicated to expanding my expertise in the field of Computing, specifically in Computer Vision, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning, to assist others.

### Languages

- Python
- TypeScript
- C/C++
- JavaScript
- Java
- HTML
- Ruby
- CSS

# Frameworks & Libraries

- Ruby on Rails
- OpenCV
- Angular 8-16
- Open3D
- Android SDK
- PyTorch
- Node.js
- TensorFlow
- Numpy
- Java Play

### Tools

- Bash/Unix Command
- Git Version Control
- PostgreSQL
- JetBrains IntelliJ
- IDEA/PyCharm
- Linux Web Server

### **Experience**

# UofSC Research Information Technology Aug. 2021 - Present IT Consultant/Developer/Graduate Research Assistant Columbia, SC

- Full Stack development of the WorldEngraved Web Interface
- Maintain and debugged source files on HPC Cluster for Snowvision Project
- Design and Implement Image Processing Algorithms for Snowvision Project
- Developing Deep Learning Models for Image Segmentation, Object Detection, and Shape Matching

# UofSC Research Information Technology June 2019 - Present World Engraves Frontend Developer

- Creating and now maintaining the user interface for the Snowvision Design matching algorithm
- Troubleshooting interface/algorithm interaction
- Designing and implementing improvements to the interface to ensure seamless interaction with the algorithm.

### CVPR (2023 - 2024) Conference

2023-2024

Peer Reviewer

# University of South Carolina (GIA) Graduate Instructing/Lab Assistant

Aug. 2022 - Dec. 2022

- Assisting Students with in-class assignments and homework questions
- Explaining concepts in programming and the Java programming language
- Demonstrating course concepts with code and other visuals

# University of South Carolina | Create-A-Thon Volunteer Web Developer Consultant

Oct. 2021

- · Strategizing and implementing solutions to improve user experience
- Collaborating with volunteer marketing strategist for designing webpage infrastructure
- Providing mentorship to visual communications students in web design

#### UofSC Research Information Technology June 2019 - Aug. 2021 Research Support Intern

- Designing and implementing user interfaces
- Documenting resource code for projects
- Testing and debugging projects
- Collaborating with clients on project design

# Nova Band Communications LLC Intern

Jan. 2014 - Aug. 2018

- Managing equipment
- Designing Cabling Infrastructures
- Updating Computer hardware
- Analysing Break fixes.

## **DEJA SCOTT**

#### **Contact Me**

**Phone** (803) 261-0957

Email ds17@email.sc.edu

GitHub https://github.com/DS-77

**LinkedIn** www.linkedin.com/in/deja-s

#### Research Intrest

Computer Vision, Image Processing, Deep Learning, and Machine Learning

#### **Awards**

- Discover UofSC 2021:
   Undergraduate Excellence and
   Outstanding Achievement Award
- Dean's List 2018-2021
- Atlantic Institute: Future Leaders
   Dialogue Dinner Attendee (2017)
- Midlands Technical College Life Scholarship (2016-2018)
- All About Education Scholar (2016)

### **Education**

Ph.D in Computer Science University of South Carolina

August 2022 - Ongoing

Master of Science in Computer Science University of South Carolina

August 2023 - Ongoing

B.S.C.S Bachelor in Computer Science University of South Carolina

August 2018 - August 2021

A.S.A.S Associate in Science Midlands Technical College

August 2016 - May 2018 Graduated with Honors

### **Research Experience**

#### Snowvision Research Project

Research Assistant

I am responsible for designing and implementing an algorithm that splits the RGB image of a cultural heritage object and pairs it with its previously split depth image. This algorithm uses contour-based shape matching to assign the RGB image to the corresponding depth image. I also maintained the algorithm source files on the HPC cluster.

#### Snowvision Research Project

Full Stack Developer

I am responsible for the frontend development of the World Engraves website, Spring Boot Server Client, and PostgreSQL database, and maintaining the connection from the Airavata Science Gateway to the HPC cluster.

#### **Snowvision Research Project**

Frontend Developer

I was responsible for the front-end development of the World Engraves website. I designed and implemented the user interface for interacting with the Snowvision Design matching algorithm.

### **Publications & Presentations**

#### Presentation

February 2024. UofSC/Lexington 1 Game Development Field Trip, Want to become a Game Developer?, Oral, Presenter

#### **Publication**

"Orthogonal Dictionary Guided Shape Completion Network for Point Cloud" AAAI, 2024 (Submission Pending)

#### Presentation

April 2021. Discover UofSC 2021, Contour-Based Shape Matching and Segmentation of Cultural Heritage Objects, Virtual. Presenter

#### **Publication**

"Snowvision: Segmenting, Identifying, and Disseminating Stamped Curve Patterns from Fragments of Pottery" International Journal of Computer Vision, 2022